randstad.ca 2018-08-15

# Randstad Privacy Policy | Randstad Canada

In accordance with applicable law, Individuals and others who collect, use and disclose personal information on Randstad Canada’s behalf must comply with the following 10 Privacy Principles.

**1.   Accountability: Fair, Lawful and Authorized manner **This Policy allows Randstad Canada to collect, use and disclose personal information for its legitimate purposes provided it does so in a fair and lawful manner.   
Randstad Canada is accountable for the Personal Information it collects and should ordinarily identify anyone to whom it will routinely disclose or transfer Personal Information, including other companies within the Randstad Group.

_Escalation Process_  
Individuals with questions or concerns about this Policy should follow the escalation process outlined as follows:

_Level 1: Privacy Ambassadors or local Branch Inquiry  
_  
As a first point of contact,

For internal employees: A Privacy Ambassador has been assigned for each branch or corporate head office for day-to-day privacy questions or concerns as well as compliance issues involving your particular branch. Please contact your direct supervisor or Branch Manager to find out the name of your particular Privacy Ambassador.  
For all other individuals: Please contact your assigned Account or Resource Manager at your local Branch.

_Level 2: Privacy Officer  
_  
If your matter cannot be resolved at the Level 1 escalation, please contact Randstad Canada’s Privacy Officer who is responsible for addressing all inquiries and complaints and ensuring compliance with this policy and applicable privacy legislation.

Privacy Officer may be reached by email at: privacyofficer@randstad.ca.

_Transferring Personal Information to Service_ Provides _(Within or Outside Canada)  
_  
Randstad Canada may transfer, process and store Personal Information outside of Canada. However, Randstad Canada only transfers Personal Information to service providers, whether within the Randstad Group or outside it (“Service Providers”), if the transfer complies with the principles and the other rules set out in this policy and with applicable privacy legislation. These Service Providers will be required to collect, use, disclose and retain Personal Information in a manner that is consistent with this Policy and applicable law.

When using Service Providers, Randstad Canada (i) employs due diligence in selecting Service Providers to process Personal Information on its behalf, (ii) imposes reasonable contractual terms on such organizations with a view to maintaining comparable data security and (iii) oversees such organizations with a view to maintaining comparable data security. 

**2\. Identifying Purposes  **The primary identified purposes for which Randstad Canada collects personal information are as follows:

In the course of its commercial activities, Randstad Canada ordinarily collects, uses and discloses Personal Information for the following reasonable business purposes:

  * to provide HR services, staffing & professional services, search & selection, recruitment and Managed Service Provider (MSP) and In-house services; and
  * to facilitate the search for, selection and recruitment of candidates.  
Randstad Canada may use online services to help it search for and recruit candidates, and may disclose information that identifies its candidates and employees to such service providers for this purpose. 

As an employer, Randstad Canada collects, uses and discloses Personal Information for the purpose of establishing, managing or terminating its employment relationships and managing and auditing its operations. These purposes include preventing and responding to work-related misconduct, breaches of law and other activities that may harm Randstad Canada’s interests. Once we establish and maintain an employment, staffing or placement relationship with our candidates, we use the data provided by the candidates, to comply with laws and regulations, including but not limited to employment law, tax and social security and national and international sanctions regulation compliance. Examples of the types of Personal Information Randstad Canada may collect at the various stages of the employment relationship include, but not limited to:  
a. Name, date of birth, gender, marital status, beneficiaries, identification numbers, including social insurance number and other identifying information, such as photographs;  
b. Background information, including education, training, work history and reference information, professional or other designations, and results from credit information and criminal record checks;  
c. Contract information, such as personal address, telephone number, cellular phone number, email address and emergency contact information;  
d. Health and medical information, including personal, emergency contact, health information of Individual’s, their spouses and dependents; and  
e. Randstad Canada work history, experience, training, compensation information and employment performance/disciplinary matters.  
Additional purposes for which Personal Information is collected shall be identified by Randstad Canada at or before the time the information is collected.

**3\. Consent  **The knowledge and consent of the individual are required for the collection, use, or disclosure of Personal Information, except where inappropriate or otherwise permissible by law.  
Randstad Canada ordinarily collects, uses and discloses Personal Information based on informed consent. Being informed means understanding the nature, purpose and consequence of the collection, use or disclosure of Personal Information. This commitment entails:

  * Informing the Individual in a meaningful way of the purposes for the collection, use or disclosure of personal data; and
  * Obtaining the Individual's consent before or at the time of collection, as well as when a new use of their Personal Information is identified.

Randstad Canada only relies on implied consent when appropriate in light of the sensitivity of Personal Information and individuals’ reasonable expectations. In particular, it relies on implied consent to collect, use and disclose the Personal Information of Individual s for the purpose of establishing, managing or terminating its employment relationships.

Exceptions to the Consent Principle  
There are a number of specific exceptions to the requirements to obtain knowledge and consent for the collection, use or disclosure of Personal Information. Examples of when the individual’s knowledge or consent is not required include, but are not limited to:

  1. Randstad Canada may collect & use Personal Information:  
a) if it is clearly in the individual's interests and consent is not available in a timely way;  
b) if knowledge and consent would compromise the availability or accuracy of the information and collection  
c) if it is required to investigate a breach of an agreement or contravention of applicable law.
  2. Randstad Canada may use & disclose Personal Information:  
a) if reasonable grounds to believe the information could be useful when investigating a contravention of applicable law and the information is used for that investigation;  
b) for an emergency that threatens an individual's life, health or security;  
c) for statistical or scholarly study or research (with notice to Privacy Commissioner of Canada).
  3. Randstad Canada may disclose Personal Information:  
a) to a lawyer representing Randstad Canada;  
b) to collect a debt the Individual owes to Randstad Canada;  
c) to comply with a subpoena, a warrant or Court Order;  
d) to an investigative body or government institution that has identified its lawful authority to obtain the information (ie for the purpose of carrying out an investigation);  
e) 20 years after the Individual 's death or 100 years after the record was created; or  
f) if required by law.

**4\. Limiting Collection for reasonable and specified purposes  **The collection of Personal Information shall be limited to that which is necessary for the purposes identified by Randstad Canada. Randstad Canada shall limit the amount and type of the information gathered to what is necessary for the identified purposes, as listed above. Randstad Canada shall only collect Personal Information for reasonable business purposes that it identifies to Individual s at the time of collection except as permitted or required by law. Randstad Canada refrains from collecting Personal Information for one purpose and then using it for another without consent except as permitted or required by law.

**5\. Limiting Use, Disclosure and Retention Only As Reasonably Necessary **Personal Information shall not be used or disclosed for purposes other than those for which it was collected, except with the consent of the Individual or as required by law. Randstad Canada maintains record retention schedules to ensure that personal Information shall be retained only as long as reasonably necessary for the fulfillment of those purposes. Randstad Canada does not retain Personal Information longer than necessary for the purposes it was collected unless required by law.

**6\. Accuracy  **Randstad Canada employs reasonable measures to ensure that Personal Information is kept as accurate as required for its purposes.   
Requests for correction of Personal Information are handled in accordance with rights granted under applicable legislation and good recordkeeping practices.  
 ****

**7.  Safeguards: Data Security & E-Communication Policy **Randstad Canada takes reasonable safeguards and security measures to protect Personal Information against unlawful or unauthorized access, disclosure, copying, use or modification. This also includes safeguarding information from loss, theft and damage. In particular, Randstad Canada maintains policies, procedures and technologies to maintain the security of Personal Information from the point of collection to the point of destruction.

Individual’s Duty to Report & Promoting compliance  
If an Individual becomes aware of any loss of, unauthorized access to, significant security lapses or unauthorized disclosure of Personal Information, whether or not he or she has caused the loss, unauthorized access or unauthorized disclosure, the Individual should must immediately raise the matter with his/her line manager or with our Privacy Officer at: privacyofficer@randstad.ca.

The reporting duty to above is an essential element of Randstad Canada’s privacy and data protection program. Randstad Canada will protect Individuals who report from reprisal and treat any failure to report as a significant employment offence.

Individuals who are contacted by a privacy regulator should promptly notify our Privacy Officer at: privacyofficer@randstad.ca.   
 ****

**8\. Openness  **Randstad Canada shall make readily available to Individuals its policies and practices to relating to the management of Personal Information.

For internal employees: this Privacy Policy is available on its intranet site in the “Employee Centre” section at <https://central.randstadgroup.ca/ec/Pages/Policies.aspx>  
For others: Randstad’s Privacy Policy can be found on Randstad’s internet site at: <https://www.randstad.ca/privacy-policy/> 

**9\. Individual Access and Correction  **In accordance with applicable law, Randstad Canada provides Individuals with access to Personal Information and a means of correcting Personal Information in accordance with applicable privacy legislation. An Individual shall be able to challenge the accuracy and completeness of the information and have it amended as appropriate. All requests for copies of Personal Information must be made in writing and directed to the Randstad Canada Privacy Officer (privacyofficer@randstad.ca).  
 ****

**10\. Recourses Available  **All complaints, questions or concerns should be brought to the local Privacy Officer at privacyofficer@randstad.ca and shall be handled in an expeditious and timely manner. If your matter has not been resolved to your satisfaction, please see the above Escalation Process section of this policy.

**  
Maintenance & Review **This Policy is effective immediately and supersedes all prior versions. The next review is scheduled for September, 2018\. Randstad Canada reserves the right to interpret this Policy at its sole discretion and to make changes as it deems appropriate from time to time without the requirement of advance notice.
